[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "রবীন্দ্রনাথ ঠাকুর",
    "options": [
      "রবীন্দ্রনাথ ঠাকুর",
      "কাজী নজরুল ইসলাম",
      "জীবনানন্দ দাশ",
      "বঙ্কিম চন্দ্র চট্টোপাধ্যায়"
    ],
    "question": "ভারতের জাতীয় সঙ্গীত 'জন গণ মন' লেখক কে?"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "কাজী নজরুল ইসলাম",
    "options": [
      "কাজী নজরুল ইসলাম",
      "রবীন্দ্রনাথ ঠাকুর",
      "জসীমউদ্দীন",
      "মাইকেল মধুসূদন দত্ত"
    ],
    "question": "বাংলা সাহিত্যে 'বিদ্রোহী কবি' হিসেবে কোন কবি পরিচিত?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "বঙ্কিম চন্দ্র চট্টোপাধ্যায়",
    "options": [
      "বঙ্কিম চন্দ্র চট্টোপাধ্যায়",
      "শরৎচন্দ্র চট্টোপাধ্যায়",
      "সরৎচন্দ্র চট্টোপাধ্যায়",
      "রবীন্দ্রনাথ ঠাকুর"
    ],
    "question": "'আনন্দমঠ' উপন্যাস লেখক কে, যা 'বন্দে মাতরম' গানের উৎস ছিল?"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "জীবনানন্দ দাশ",
    "options": [
      "জীবনানন্দ দাশ",
      "রবীন্দ্রনাথ ঠাকুর",
      "কাজী নজরুল ইসলাম",
      "সুকান্ত ভট্টাচার্য"
    ],
    "question": "কোন কবি তার আধুনিকতা ও অস্বাভাবিক কবিতার জন্য পরিচিত ছিলেন বাংলা সাহিত্যে?"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "রাজা রামমোহন রায়",
    "options": [
      "রাজা রামমোহন রায়",
      "ঈশ্বরচন্দ্র বিদ্যাসাগর",
      "স্বামী বিবেকানন্দ",
      "সুভাষ চন্দ্র বোস"
    ],
    "question": "কে একজন প্রমিনেন্ট সামাজিক সংস্কারক এবং ব্রাহ্ম সমাজের প্রতিষ্ঠাতা ছিলেন?"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "দুর্গা পূজা",
    "options": ["দুর্গা পূজা", "দিপাবলি", "হোলি", "ঈদ"],
    "question": "পশ্চিমবঙ্গ এবং বাংলাদেশে পূজা অবসরে উৎসবস্পর্ধা সহ প্রধান হিন্দু উৎসব কোনটি?"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "কোলকাতা",
    "options": ["কোলকাতা", "ঢাকা", "চট্টগ্রাম", "খুলনা"],
    "question": "ভারতের পশ্চিমবঙ্গ রাজ্যের রাজধানী কি?"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "বাংলাদেশ",
    "options": ["বাংলাদেশ", "ভারত", "মায়ানমার", "নেপাল"],
    "question": "ভারতের পশ্চিমবঙ্গ রাজ্যের পূর্বে কোন দেশ অবস্থিত?"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "ঢাকা",
    "options": ["ঢাকা", "চট্টগ্রাম", "খুলনা", "রাজশাহী"],
    "question": "বাংলাদেশের রাজধানী কি?"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "বাংলা",
    "options": ["বাংলা", "হিন্দি", "তামিল", "উর্দু"],
    "question": "পশ্চিমবঙ্গ এবং বাংলাদেশে প্রধানভাবে কোন ভাষা বলা হয়?"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "সীতার",
    "options": ["সীতার", "তবলা", "বাঁশী", "ঢোল"],
    "question": "ভারত এবং বাংলাদেশের শাস্ত্রীয় সঙ্গীতের সাথে সাধারণভাবে সংযুক্ত একটি প্রসিদ্ধ সঙ্গীতবাদ্যের নাম কি?"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "পহেলা বৈশাখ",
    "options": ["পহেলা বৈশাখ", "দীপাবলি", "ঈদ-উল-ফিতর", "খ্রিস্টমাস"],
    "question": "বাংলাদেশ এবং পশ্চিমবঙ্গে 'বাংলা নববর্ষ' উদযাপন কি নামে পরিচিত?"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "কাজী নজরুল ইসলাম",
    "options": [
      "কাজী নজরুল ইসলাম",
      "রবীন্দ্রনাথ ঠাকুর",
      "জসীমউদ্দীন",
      "মাইকেল মধুসূদন দত্ত"
    ],
    "question": "কে বাংলাদেশের 'জাতীয় কবি' হিসেবে পরিচিত?"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "আম",
    "options": ["আম", "কলা", "আনারস", "কমলা"],
    "question": "বাংলাদেশের জাতীয় ফল কি?"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "বায়তুল মোকাররম",
    "options": [
      "বায়তুল মোকাররম",
      "জাতীয় সংসদ ভবন",
      "লালবাগ দূর্গ",
      "আহসান মঞ্জিল"
    ],
    "question": "ঢাকা, বাংলাদেশের হৃদয়ে অবস্থিত প্রসিদ্ধ মসজিদের নাম কি?"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "সাহিত্যে নোবেল পুরস্কার",
    "options": [
      "সাহিত্যে নোবেল পুরস্কার",
      "নোবেল শান্তি পুরস্কার",
      "নোবেল পদার্থবিজ্ঞান পুরস্কার",
      "নোবেল রাসায়নিক বিজ্ঞান পুরস্কার"
    ],
    "question": "রবীন্দ্রনাথ ঠাকুরকে কোন অবসানে নোবেল পুরস্কার দেওয়া হয়েছে?"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "জুট",
    "options": ["জুট", "চা", "ধান", "কাপাস"],
    "question": "বাংলাদেশ সৃজন করার জন্য প্রসিদ্ধ কোন প্রাকৃতিক তন্তু সেজে তোলে?"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "শাহজালাল আন্তর্জাতিক বিমানবন্দর",
    "options": [
      "শাহজালাল আন্তর্জাতিক বিমানবন্দর",
      "হযরত শাহ জালাল বিজ্ঞান ও প্রযুক্তি বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়",
      "শাহজালাল বিজ্ঞান ও প্রযুক্তি বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়",
      "শাহজালাল ইসলামী ব্যাংক"
    ],
    "question": "বাংলাদেশের সবচেয়ে বড় আন্তর্জাতিক বিমানবন্দর কোনটি?"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "সুন্দরবন",
    "options": ["সুন্দরবন", "চট্টগ্রাম পাহাড়", "কক্সবাজার", "সিলেট"],
    "question": "বাংলাদেশে কোন বনে বাঘ বাস করে এবং সেখানে বাংলা বাঘ বলে পরিচিত?"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "পুথি",
    "options": ["পুথি", "কাঁথা", "নকশি কাঁথা", "বাটিক"],
    "question": "বাংলাদেশে 'সুই ব্যাপারের লোক' আর 'এইচসিএসসি' হতে চাইলে আপনি কোন পারম্পরিক লোকের দ্বারা তায়ারি হতে পারেন?"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "বাংলা নববর্ষ",
    "options": ["বাংলা নববর্ষ", "খ্রিস্টমাস", "ঈদ-উল-ফিতর", "পহেলা বৈশাখ"],
    "question": "পশ্চিমবঙ্গ এবং বাংলাদেশে 'বাংলা পত্রিকার বছরের শেষে প্রকাশ হয়?' উপন্যাসের শিরোনাম কী?"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "ইলিশ",
    "options": ["ইলিশ", "চিংড়ি", "রুই", "শিং"],
    "question": "বাংলা রান্নার জনপ্রিয় মাছ কী?"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "আমার সোনার বাংলা",
    "options": [
      "আমার সোনার বাংলা",
      "জন গণ মন",
      "ভান্ডে মাতরম",
      "সারে জাহান সে আছা"
    ],
    "question": "বাংলাদেশের জাতীয় সঙ্গীতের নাম কি?"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "বাংলা",
    "options": ["বাংলা", "হিন্দি", "তামিল", "উর্দু"],
    "question": "বাংলাদেশের আধিকারিক ভাষা কি?"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "subject": "বাংলা",
    "correctAnswer": "মুজিবনগর",
    "options": ["মুজিবনগর", "ঢাকা", "চট্টগ্রাম", "খুলনা"],
    "question": "1971 সাধারণ মানুষের মুক্তির যুদ্ধে বাংলাদেশের স্থায়ী সরকার কোথায় স্থাপন করা হয়েছিল?"
  },

  {
    "id": 26,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Periodic Table",
    "options": [
      "Periodic Table",
      "Chemical Equation",
      "Molecular Formula",
      "Chemical Bond"
    ],
    "question": "What is the tabular arrangement of chemical elements called?"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Hydrogen",
    "options": ["Hydrogen", "Oxygen", "Carbon", "Nitrogen"],
    "question": "What is the lightest and most abundant element in the universe?"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "H2O",
    "options": ["H2O", "CO2", "O2", "N2"],
    "question": "What is the chemical formula for water?"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Chemical reaction",
    "options": [
      "Chemical reaction",
      "Physical change",
      "Nuclear reaction",
      "Phase transition"
    ],
    "question": "What is the process that leads to the transformation of one or more substances into different substances?"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Valence electrons",
    "options": ["Valence electrons", "Protons", "Neutrons", "Electrons"],
    "question": "What are the electrons in the outermost energy level of an atom called?"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Molecule",
    "options": ["Molecule", "Atom", "Ion", "Element"],
    "question": "What is the smallest unit of a compound that retains its chemical properties?"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Acid",
    "options": ["Acid", "Base", "Salt", "Alkali"],
    "question": "A substance with a pH value less than 7 is known as what?"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Alkali metals",
    "options": [
      "Alkali metals",
      "Transition metals",
      "Halogens",
      "Noble gases"
    ],
    "question": "Which group of elements includes lithium, sodium, and potassium?"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Chemical bond",
    "options": [
      "Chemical bond",
      "Ionic bond",
      "Covalent bond",
      "Hydrogen bond"
    ],
    "question": "What is the force that holds atoms together in a molecule?"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Catalyst",
    "options": ["Catalyst", "Reactant", "Product", "Inhibitor"],
    "question": "What is a substance that increases the rate of a chemical reaction without being consumed in the process?"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "pH scale",
    "options": ["pH scale", "Litmus paper", "Thermometer", "Barometer"],
    "question": "What is used to measure the acidity or alkalinity of a solution?"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Noble gases",
    "options": [
      "Noble gases",
      "Halogens",
      "Alkali metals",
      "Transition metals"
    ],
    "question": "Which group of elements includes helium, neon, and argon?"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Organic chemistry",
    "options": [
      "Organic chemistry",
      "Inorganic chemistry",
      "Physical chemistry",
      "Analytical chemistry"
    ],
    "question": "Which branch of chemistry deals with carbon compounds and their properties?"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Oxidation",
    "options": ["Oxidation", "Reduction", "Combustion", "Decomposition"],
    "question": "What chemical process involves the loss of electrons or an increase in oxidation state?"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Isotope",
    "options": ["Isotope", "Ion", "Molecule", "Element"],
    "question": "What is an atom with the same number of protons but a different number of neutrons called?"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Enzyme",
    "options": ["Enzyme", "Catalyst", "Substrate", "Product"],
    "question": "What type of protein acts as a biological catalyst in living organisms?"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Electrolysis",
    "options": ["Electrolysis", "Evaporation", "Filtration", "Distillation"],
    "question": "What process involves the use of an electric current to drive a non-spontaneous chemical reaction?"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Covalent bond",
    "options": [
      "Covalent bond",
      "Ionic bond",
      "Metallic bond",
      "Hydrogen bond"
    ],
    "question": "What type of chemical bond involves the sharing of electrons between atoms?"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Mole",
    "options": ["Mole", "Gram", "Liter", "Kilogram"],
    "question": "What is the SI unit for the amount of substance?"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Avogadro's number",
    "options": [
      "Avogadro's number",
      "Planck's constant",
      "Boltzmann's constant",
      "Faraday's constant"
    ],
    "question": "What is the number of atoms, ions, or molecules in one mole of a substance?"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Thermodynamics",
    "options": [
      "Thermodynamics",
      "Kinetics",
      "Quantum mechanics",
      "Electrochemistry"
    ],
    "question": "What branch of chemistry deals with the study of energy changes in chemical reactions?"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Titration",
    "options": ["Titration", "Extraction", "Decomposition", "Combustion"],
    "question": "What laboratory technique is used to determine the concentration of a substance in a solution?"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Atomic number",
    "options": [
      "Atomic number",
      "Atomic mass",
      "Valence electrons",
      "Isotopic mass"
    ],
    "question": "What unique number identifies an element and represents the number of protons in its nucleus?"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Chemical equilibrium",
    "options": [
      "Chemical equilibrium",
      "Chemical reaction",
      "Chemical kinetics",
      "Chemical bonding"
    ],
    "question": "What state is reached in a reversible chemical reaction when the rates of forward and reverse reactions are equal?"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "subject": "Chemistry",
    "correctAnswer": "Hydrochloric acid",
    "options": [
      "Hydrochloric acid",
      "Sulfuric acid",
      "Nitric acid",
      "Acetic acid"
    ],
    "question": "What is the strong acid commonly found in the human stomach?"
  },

  {
    "id": 51,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Mitochondria",
    "options": ["Mitochondria", "Nucleus", "Ribosome", "Golgi apparatus"],
    "question": "Which organelle is known as the 'powerhouse of the cell' and produces ATP?"
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "DNA",
    "options": ["DNA", "RNA", "Protein", "Lipid"],
    "question": "What is the hereditary material found in cells that contains genetic information?"
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Photosynthesis",
    "options": ["Photosynthesis", "Respiration", "Fermentation", "Digestion"],
    "question": "What is the process by which green plants and some other organisms convert light energy into chemical energy?"
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Cell wall",
    "options": ["Cell wall", "Cell membrane", "Cytoplasm", "Nucleus"],
    "question": "In plant cells, what provides structural support and protection to the cell?"
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Hormones",
    "options": ["Hormones", "Antibodies", "Enzymes", "Neurotransmitters"],
    "question": "Chemical messengers produced by glands and transported through the bloodstream are known as what?"
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Evolution",
    "options": ["Evolution", "Adaptation", "Natural selection", "Genetics"],
    "question": "The process by which species change over time and develop new traits is called what?"
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Eukaryotic",
    "options": ["Eukaryotic", "Prokaryotic", "Asexual", "Heterotrophic"],
    "question": "Are human cells eukaryotic or prokaryotic?"
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Oxygen",
    "options": ["Oxygen", "Carbon dioxide", "Nitrogen", "Hydrogen"],
    "question": "What gas do humans and animals breathe in for respiration?"
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Asexual reproduction",
    "options": [
      "Asexual reproduction",
      "Sexual reproduction",
      "Binary fission",
      "Budding"
    ],
    "question": "What type of reproduction involves the production of offspring without the involvement of gametes?"
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Nervous system",
    "options": [
      "Nervous system",
      "Circulatory system",
      "Digestive system",
      "Respiratory system"
    ],
    "question": "Which body system is responsible for transmitting signals between different parts of the body?"
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Charles Darwin",
    "options": [
      "Charles Darwin",
      "Gregor Mendel",
      "Alfred Wallace",
      "Louis Pasteur"
    ],
    "question": "Who is famous for the theory of natural selection in evolution?"
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Bacteria",
    "options": ["Bacteria", "Viruses", "Fungi", "Protozoa"],
    "question": "What are single-celled microorganisms that can be both beneficial and harmful to humans?"
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Genotype",
    "options": ["Genotype", "Phenotype", "Allele", "Chromosome"],
    "question": "What term refers to the genetic makeup of an individual organism?"
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Enzymes",
    "options": ["Enzymes", "Hormones", "Antibodies", "Neurotransmitters"],
    "question": "Proteins that act as biological catalysts to speed up chemical reactions in living organisms are called what?"
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Endocrine system",
    "options": [
      "Endocrine system",
      "Immune system",
      "Digestive system",
      "Circulatory system"
    ],
    "question": "What system in the body is responsible for producing and regulating hormones?"
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Ecology",
    "options": ["Ecology", "Botany", "Zoology", "Genetics"],
    "question": "The study of interactions between organisms and their environment is known as what?"
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Fungi",
    "options": ["Fungi", "Plants", "Animals", "Protists"],
    "question": "Which kingdom of organisms includes mushrooms, yeasts, and molds?"
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Respiration",
    "options": ["Respiration", "Photosynthesis", "Fermentation", "Digestion"],
    "question": "What is the process by which organisms obtain energy from the oxidation of glucose or other organic molecules?"
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "DNA replication",
    "options": ["DNA replication", "Transcription", "Translation", "Mutation"],
    "question": "What is the process by which a DNA molecule makes an identical copy of itself?"
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Adaptation",
    "options": ["Adaptation", "Evolution", "Mutation", "Natural selection"],
    "question": "The process by which an organism becomes better suited to its environment is called what?"
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Cellulose",
    "options": ["Cellulose", "Starch", "Glycogen", "Chitin"],
    "question": "What is the main structural component of plant cell walls?"
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Digestive system",
    "options": [
      "Digestive system",
      "Circulatory system",
      "Respiratory system",
      "Nervous system"
    ],
    "question": "What system in the body is responsible for breaking down food and absorbing nutrients?"
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "RNA",
    "options": ["RNA", "DNA", "Protein", "Lipid"],
    "question": "Which molecule plays a crucial role in protein synthesis and is responsible for carrying genetic information from DNA to ribosomes?"
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Golgi apparatus",
    "options": [
      "Golgi apparatus",
      "Endoplasmic reticulum",
      "Ribosome",
      "Lysosome"
    ],
    "question": "Which organelle is involved in packaging and modifying proteins for transport within the cell?"
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "subject": "Biology",
    "correctAnswer": "Chloroplasts",
    "options": [
      "Chloroplasts",
      "Mitochondria",
      "Nucleus",
      "Endoplasmic reticulum"
    ],
    "question": "In plant cells, where does photosynthesis primarily take place?"
  },

  {
    "id": 76,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Newton's First Law of Motion",
    "options": [
      "Newton's First Law of Motion",
      "Newton's Second Law of Motion",
      "Newton's Third Law of Motion",
      "Law of Gravitation"
    ],
    "question": "Which law of motion states that an object at rest will remain at rest, and an object in motion will remain in motion unless acted upon by an external force?"
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Velocity",
    "options": ["Velocity", "Speed", "Acceleration", "Distance"],
    "question": "What term describes the speed of an object in a particular direction?"
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Momentum",
    "options": ["Momentum", "Force", "Energy", "Acceleration"],
    "question": "What is the product of an object's mass and its velocity?"
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Electromagnetic Spectrum",
    "options": [
      "Electromagnetic Spectrum",
      "Sound Spectrum",
      "Light Spectrum",
      "Radio Spectrum"
    ],
    "question": "What is the range of all types of electromagnetic radiation arranged by frequency and wavelength?"
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Albert Einstein",
    "options": [
      "Albert Einstein",
      "Isaac Newton",
      "Galileo Galilei",
      "Niels Bohr"
    ],
    "question": "Who formulated the theory of relativity, including the famous equation E=mc^2?"
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Inertia",
    "options": ["Inertia", "Gravity", "Friction", "Acceleration"],
    "question": "What is the resistance of any physical object to any change in its velocity?"
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Ohm's Law",
    "options": ["Ohm's Law", "Faraday's Law", "Ampere's Law", "Gauss's Law"],
    "question": "Which law relates the current flowing through a conductor to the voltage and resistance?"
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Wave-particle duality",
    "options": [
      "Wave-particle duality",
      "Quantum entanglement",
      "Heisenberg's Uncertainty Principle",
      "Photoelectric effect"
    ],
    "question": "What concept in quantum mechanics suggests that particles like electrons exhibit both wave-like and particle-like properties?"
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Nuclear Fusion",
    "options": [
      "Nuclear Fusion",
      "Nuclear Fission",
      "Radioactive Decay",
      "Neutron Emission"
    ],
    "question": "What process powers the sun and other stars by combining hydrogen atoms to form helium?"
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Refraction",
    "options": ["Refraction", "Reflection", "Diffraction", "Dispersion"],
    "question": "The bending of light as it passes from one medium to another with different optical densities is known as what?"
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Kinetic Energy",
    "options": [
      "Kinetic Energy",
      "Potential Energy",
      "Mechanical Energy",
      "Thermal Energy"
    ],
    "question": "The energy of an object due to its motion is called what?"
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Quantum Mechanics",
    "options": [
      "Quantum Mechanics",
      "Classical Mechanics",
      "Relativistic Mechanics",
      "Thermodynamics"
    ],
    "question": "Which branch of physics deals with the behavior of particles at the quantum level?"
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Sound Waves",
    "options": [
      "Sound Waves",
      "Electromagnetic Waves",
      "Gravity Waves",
      "Radio Waves"
    ],
    "question": "What type of waves require a medium, such as air or water, for propagation?"
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Infrared",
    "options": ["Infrared", "Ultraviolet", "X-ray", "Microwave"],
    "question": "Which region of the electromagnetic spectrum has longer wavelengths than visible light and is often used for thermal imaging?"
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Coulomb's Law",
    "options": [
      "Coulomb's Law",
      "Newton's Law of Universal Gravitation",
      "Ohm's Law",
      "Ampere's Law"
    ],
    "question": "What law describes the electrostatic force between charged objects?"
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Quantum Electrodynamics (QED)",
    "options": [
      "Quantum Electrodynamics (QED)",
      "General Theory of Relativity",
      "String Theory",
      "Quantum Field Theory"
    ],
    "question": "Which theory describes the electromagnetic force and is a part of the Standard Model of particle physics?"
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Gravitational Force",
    "options": [
      "Gravitational Force",
      "Electromagnetic Force",
      "Strong Nuclear Force",
      "Weak Nuclear Force"
    ],
    "question": "What fundamental force is responsible for the attraction between masses?"
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Quantum Tunneling",
    "options": [
      "Quantum Tunneling",
      "Quantum Entanglement",
      "Quantum Superposition",
      "Quantum Decoherence"
    ],
    "question": "What quantum phenomenon allows particles to pass through energy barriers that classical physics predicts they cannot overcome?"
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Thermodynamics",
    "options": [
      "Thermodynamics",
      "Electromagnetism",
      "Quantum Mechanics",
      "Relativity"
    ],
    "question": "Which branch of physics deals with the study of heat, energy, and work?"
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Nuclear Reactor",
    "options": [
      "Nuclear Reactor",
      "Particle Accelerator",
      "Telescope",
      "Microscope"
    ],
    "question": "What device is designed to initiate and control a nuclear chain reaction for various purposes?"
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Electron",
    "options": ["Electron", "Proton", "Neutron", "Photon"],
    "question": "What subatomic particle has a negative charge and orbits the nucleus of an atom?"
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Escape Velocity",
    "options": [
      "Escape Velocity",
      "Terminal Velocity",
      "Initial Velocity",
      "Final Velocity"
    ],
    "question": "The minimum velocity an object must reach to break free from a celestial body's gravitational attraction is called what?"
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Superconductivity",
    "options": [
      "Superconductivity",
      "Superfluidity",
      "Supersymmetry",
      "Supergravity"
    ],
    "question": "What phenomenon occurs in certain materials at low temperatures where electrical resistance drops to zero?"
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Nuclear Decay",
    "options": [
      "Nuclear Decay",
      "Nuclear Fusion",
      "Nuclear Fission",
      "Nuclear Chain Reaction"
    ],
    "question": "The spontaneous disintegration of an unstable atomic nucleus is known as what?"
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "subject": "Physics",
    "correctAnswer": "Quantum Entanglement",
    "options": [
      "Quantum Entanglement",
      "Quantum Superposition",
      "Quantum Tunneling",
      "Quantum Decoherence"
    ],
    "question": "What quantum phenomenon links the properties of particles even when they are separated by large distances?"
  },

  {
    "id": 101,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Derivative",
    "options": ["Derivative", "Integral", "Limit", "Matrix"],
    "question": "What mathematical operation represents the rate of change of a function?"
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Euler's Number (e)",
    "options": [
      "Euler's Number (e)",
      "Pi (π)",
      "Golden Ratio (φ)",
      "Imaginary Unit (i)"
    ],
    "question": "What mathematical constant is the base of the natural logarithm and approximately equal to 2.71828?"
  },
  {
    "id": 103,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Calculus",
    "options": ["Calculus", "Algebra", "Geometry", "Statistics"],
    "question": "What branch of mathematics deals with rates of change and accumulation of quantities?"
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Taylor Series",
    "options": [
      "Taylor Series",
      "Fourier Series",
      "Maclaurin Series",
      "Power Series"
    ],
    "question": "What mathematical series represents a function as an infinite sum of terms derived from its derivatives?"
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Vector Space",
    "options": ["Vector Space", "Scalar Field", "Matrix Space", "Tensor Space"],
    "question": "In linear algebra, what is a set of vectors closed under vector addition and scalar multiplication?"
  },
  {
    "id": 106,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Eigenvalue",
    "options": ["Eigenvalue", "Eigenvector", "Determinant", "Transpose"],
    "question": "In linear algebra, what is a scalar associated with a matrix representing a transformation?"
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Partial Derivative",
    "options": [
      "Partial Derivative",
      "Total Derivative",
      "Integral",
      "Differential Equation"
    ],
    "question": "In multivariable calculus, what type of derivative measures how a function changes with respect to one variable while holding others constant?"
  },
  {
    "id": 108,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Riemann Integral",
    "options": [
      "Riemann Integral",
      "Lebesgue Integral",
      "Definite Integral",
      "Indefinite Integral"
    ],
    "question": "What type of integral is used to find the area under a curve by dividing it into small rectangles?"
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Complex Analysis",
    "options": [
      "Complex Analysis",
      "Real Analysis",
      "Functional Analysis",
      "Harmonic Analysis"
    ],
    "question": "What branch of mathematics deals with functions of complex numbers?"
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Differential Equation",
    "options": [
      "Differential Equation",
      "Integral Equation",
      "Linear Equation",
      "Quadratic Equation"
    ],
    "question": "What type of equation involves an unknown function and its derivatives?"
  },
  {
    "id": 111,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Number Theory",
    "options": ["Number Theory", "Set Theory", "Graph Theory", "Topology"],
    "question": "What branch of mathematics focuses on properties and relationships of numbers, especially integers?"
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Topology",
    "options": ["Topology", "Geometry", "Algebra", "Analysis"],
    "question": "What branch of mathematics studies properties of space that are preserved under continuous deformations?"
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Group Theory",
    "options": [
      "Group Theory",
      "Ring Theory",
      "Field Theory",
      "Vector Space Theory"
    ],
    "question": "What branch of abstract algebra deals with the concept of symmetry and transformations?"
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Matrices",
    "options": ["Matrices", "Vectors", "Scalars", "Tensors"],
    "question": "In linear algebra, what are rectangular arrays of numbers used to represent linear transformations?"
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Prime Number",
    "options": [
      "Prime Number",
      "Composite Number",
      "Rational Number",
      "Irrational Number"
    ],
    "question": "What is a natural number greater than 1 that has no positive divisors other than 1 and itself?"
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Convergence",
    "options": ["Convergence", "Divergence", "Limit", "Series"],
    "question": "In calculus, what term refers to the behavior of a sequence or function approaching a definite value?"
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Set Theory",
    "options": ["Set Theory", "Number Theory", "Graph Theory", "Topology"],
    "question": "What branch of mathematics deals with the study of sets and their properties?"
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Arithmetic Mean",
    "options": ["Arithmetic Mean", "Geometric Mean", "Harmonic Mean", "Median"],
    "question": "What is the average of a set of numbers obtained by adding them together and dividing by the count?"
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Bayes' Theorem",
    "options": [
      "Bayes' Theorem",
      "Fermat's Last Theorem",
      "Euler's Formula",
      "Pythagorean Theorem"
    ],
    "question": "What theorem in probability theory relates conditional probabilities?"
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Hilbert Space",
    "options": [
      "Hilbert Space",
      "Euclidean Space",
      "Minkowski Space",
      "Banach Space"
    ],
    "question": "In functional analysis, what is a complete inner product space?"
  },
  {
    "id": 121,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Eigenvector",
    "options": ["Eigenvector", "Eigenvalue", "Determinant", "Transpose"],
    "question": "In linear algebra, what is a vector that remains unchanged in direction when a linear transformation is applied?"
  },
  {
    "id": 122,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Gamma Function",
    "options": [
      "Gamma Function",
      "Beta Function",
      "Delta Function",
      "Zeta Function"
    ],
    "question": "What function extends the factorial function to real and complex numbers?"
  },
  {
    "id": 123,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Non-Euclidean Geometry",
    "options": [
      "Non-Euclidean Geometry",
      "Euclidean Geometry",
      "Analytic Geometry",
      "Differential Geometry"
    ],
    "question": "What branch of geometry explores geometries where the parallel postulate does not hold?"
  },
  {
    "id": 124,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Hyperbolic Functions",
    "options": [
      "Hyperbolic Functions",
      "Trigonometric Functions",
      "Exponential Functions",
      "Logarithmic Functions"
    ],
    "question": "What class of functions is analog to trigonometric functions but deals with hyperbolas?"
  },
  {
    "id": 125,
    "subject": "Higher Mathematics",
    "correctAnswer": "Topology",
    "options": ["Topology", "Geometry", "Algebra", "Analysis"],
    "question": "What branch of mathematics studies properties of space that are preserved under continuous deformations?"
  },

  {
    "id": 126,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Metaphor",
    "options": ["Metaphor", "Simile", "Hyperbole", "Personification"],
    "question": "What figure of speech involves a direct comparison between two unlike things, often using 'is' or 'was'?"
  },
  {
    "id": 127,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Alliteration",
    "options": ["Alliteration", "Assonance", "Consonance", "Onomatopoeia"],
    "question": "What is the repetition of initial consonant sounds in a series of words within a phrase or verse?"
  },
  {
    "id": 128,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Antonym",
    "options": ["Antonym", "Synonym", "Homonym", "Homophone"],
    "question": "What term refers to a word that has the opposite meaning of another word?"
  },
  {
    "id": 129,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Irony",
    "options": ["Irony", "Sarcasm", "Satire", "Parody"],
    "question": "What literary device involves a discrepancy between appearance and reality?"
  },
  {
    "id": 130,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Theme",
    "options": ["Theme", "Plot", "Character", "Setting"],
    "question": "What is the central idea or message of a literary work?"
  },
  {
    "id": 131,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Simile",
    "options": ["Simile", "Metaphor", "Hyperbole", "Personification"],
    "question": "What figure of speech involves a comparison between two unlike things using 'like' or 'as'?"
  },
  {
    "id": 132,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Foreshadowing",
    "options": ["Foreshadowing", "Flashback", "Symbolism", "Imagery"],
    "question": "What literary technique hints at events that will occur later in a story?"
  },
  {
    "id": 133,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Oxymoron",
    "options": ["Oxymoron", "Paradox", "Hyperbole", "Irony"],
    "question": "What is a figure of speech that combines contradictory or opposite words for effect?"
  },
  {
    "id": 134,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Sonnet",
    "options": ["Sonnet", "Haiku", "Limerick", "Epic"],
    "question": "What is a 14-line poem with a specific rhyme scheme, often associated with Shakespeare?"
  },
  {
    "id": 135,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Syntax",
    "options": ["Syntax", "Semantics", "Pragmatics", "Morphology"],
    "question": "What refers to the arrangement of words and phrases to create well-formed sentences in a language?"
  },
  {
    "id": 136,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Allegory",
    "options": ["Allegory", "Parable", "Fable", "Myth"],
    "question": "What is a story, poem, or picture that can be interpreted to reveal a hidden meaning, typically a moral or political one?"
  },
  {
    "id": 137,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Antagonist",
    "options": ["Antagonist", "Protagonist", "Narrator", "Foil"],
    "question": "Who is the character or force that opposes the protagonist in a story?"
  },
  {
    "id": 138,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Haiku",
    "options": ["Haiku", "Sonnet", "Limerick", "Epic"],
    "question": "What is a form of Japanese poetry consisting of three lines with syllable counts of 5, 7, and 5?"
  },
  {
    "id": 139,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Mood",
    "options": ["Mood", "Tone", "Style", "Voice"],
    "question": "What literary element refers to the emotional atmosphere or feeling created by a work of literature?"
  },
  {
    "id": 140,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Epiphany",
    "options": ["Epiphany", "Conflict", "Resolution", "Climax"],
    "question": "What is a moment of sudden realization or insight experienced by a character in a story?"
  },
  {
    "id": 141,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Consonance",
    "options": ["Consonance", "Assonance", "Alliteration", "Onomatopoeia"],
    "question": "What is the repetition of consonant sounds in the middle or at the end of words?"
  },
  {
    "id": 142,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Denouement",
    "options": ["Denouement", "Exposition", "Climax", "Resolution"],
    "question": "What is the final part of a story where loose ends are tied up and the outcome becomes clear?"
  },
  {
    "id": 143,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Hyperbole",
    "options": ["Hyperbole", "Metonymy", "Synecdoche", "Litotes"],
    "question": "What is a figure of speech involving exaggeration for emphasis or effect?"
  },
  {
    "id": 144,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Cliché",
    "options": ["Cliché", "Stereotype", "Juxtaposition", "Irony"],
    "question": "What is an overused phrase or expression that has lost its originality or impact?"
  },
  {
    "id": 145,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Satire",
    "options": ["Satire", "Parody", "Sarcasm", "Irony"],
    "question": "What is a literary technique that uses humor, irony, or ridicule to criticize or mock human vices or shortcomings?"
  },
  {
    "id": 146,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Paradox",
    "options": ["Paradox", "Oxymoron", "Antithesis", "Juxtaposition"],
    "question": "What is a statement or situation that appears contradictory but may reveal a deeper truth?"
  },
  {
    "id": 147,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Symbolism",
    "options": ["Symbolism", "Allegory", "Metaphor", "Simile"],
    "question": "What literary device uses symbols to represent ideas, qualities, or concepts?"
  },
  {
    "id": 148,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Diction",
    "options": ["Diction", "Syntax", "Rhetoric", "Semantics"],
    "question": "What refers to the choice and use of words and phrases in speech or writing?"
  },
  {
    "id": 149,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Soliloquy",
    "options": ["Soliloquy", "Monologue", "Dialogue", "Aside"],
    "question": "What is a dramatic speech delivered by a character alone on stage to express their inner thoughts and feelings?"
  },
  {
    "id": 150,
    "subject": "English",
    "correctAnswer": "Foreshadowing",
    "options": ["Foreshadowing", "Flashback", "Symbolism", "Imagery"],
    "question": "What literary technique hints at events that will occur later in a story?"
  },

  {
    "id": 151,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Internet Protocol (IP)",
    "options": [
      "Internet Protocol (IP)",
      "Transmission Control Protocol (TCP)",
      "File Transfer Protocol (FTP)",
      "Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP)"
    ],
    "question": "What protocol is responsible for addressing and routing packets of data so that they can travel across networks and arrive at the correct destination?"
  },
  {
    "id": 152,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Cybersecurity",
    "options": ["Cybersecurity", "Firewall", "Encryption", "Malware"],
    "question": "What field of ICT focuses on protecting computer systems and networks from unauthorized access, attacks, and damage?"
  },
  {
    "id": 153,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Cloud Computing",
    "options": [
      "Cloud Computing",
      "Big Data",
      "Artificial Intelligence",
      "Blockchain"
    ],
    "question": "What technology allows users to access and use computing resources and services over the internet, often on a pay-as-you-go basis?"
  },
  {
    "id": 154,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Database Management System (DBMS)",
    "options": [
      "Database Management System (DBMS)",
      "Operating System (OS)",
      "Web Browser",
      "Spreadsheets"
    ],
    "question": "What software is used to create, manage, and manipulate databases?"
  },
  {
    "id": 155,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Firewall",
    "options": ["Firewall", "Antivirus Software", "Malware", "Phishing"],
    "question": "What is a network security device or software that monitors and filters incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules?"
  },
  {
    "id": 156,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Artificial Intelligence (AI)",
    "options": [
      "Artificial Intelligence (AI)",
      "Machine Learning",
      "Robotics",
      "Natural Language Processing (NLP)"
    ],
    "question": "What field of ICT focuses on creating computer systems that can perform tasks that typically require human intelligence?"
  },
  {
    "id": 157,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Encryption",
    "options": ["Encryption", "Decryption", "Cryptography", "Hacking"],
    "question": "What process converts plaintext into ciphertext to secure information from unauthorized access or modification?"
  },
  {
    "id": 158,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "URL (Uniform Resource Locator)",
    "options": [
      "URL (Uniform Resource Locator)",
      "IP Address",
      "DNS (Domain Name System)",
      "HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol)"
    ],
    "question": "What is the address used to access resources on the World Wide Web?"
  },
  {
    "id": 159,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Malware",
    "options": ["Malware", "Spyware", "Adware", "Phishing"],
    "question": "What term encompasses various types of malicious software designed to harm or exploit computer systems and data?"
  },
  {
    "id": 160,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Operating System (OS)",
    "options": [
      "Operating System (OS)",
      "Software Application",
      "Hardware Component",
      "Peripheral Device"
    ],
    "question": "What system software manages computer hardware and provides common services for computer programs?"
  },
  {
    "id": 161,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Blockchain",
    "options": [
      "Blockchain",
      "Cryptocurrency",
      "Smart Contract",
      "Distributed Ledger"
    ],
    "question": "What technology is a decentralized and distributed digital ledger used to record transactions across multiple computers?"
  },
  {
    "id": 162,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Phishing",
    "options": ["Phishing", "Spoofing", "Denial of Service (DoS)", "Virus"],
    "question": "What is a cyber attack method that involves tricking individuals into revealing sensitive information or performing actions they shouldn't?"
  },
  {
    "id": 163,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "LAN (Local Area Network)",
    "options": [
      "LAN (Local Area Network)",
      "WAN (Wide Area Network)",
      "MAN (Metropolitan Area Network)",
      "VPN (Virtual Private Network)"
    ],
    "question": "What type of network connects computers and devices within a limited geographical area, such as a home, office, or campus?"
  },
  {
    "id": 164,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Spreadsheets",
    "options": [
      "Spreadsheets",
      "Word Processors",
      "Presentation Software",
      "Database Software"
    ],
    "question": "What type of software is commonly used for tasks involving numerical calculations, data analysis, and tabular data management?"
  },
  {
    "id": 165,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "IP Address",
    "options": [
      "IP Address",
      "MAC Address",
      "DNS (Domain Name System)",
      "URL (Uniform Resource Locator)"
    ],
    "question": "What unique numeric label is assigned to each device participating in a computer network that uses the Internet Protocol for communication?"
  },
  {
    "id": 166,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Cyberbullying",
    "options": ["Cyberbullying", "Phishing", "Hacking", "Malware"],
    "question": "What is the use of electronic communication to harass or intimidate others, typically through social media or online platforms?"
  },
  {
    "id": 167,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Distributed Computing",
    "options": [
      "Distributed Computing",
      "Centralized Computing",
      "Parallel Computing",
      "Cloud Computing"
    ],
    "question": "What computing model involves multiple computers working together on a task, often in a decentralized manner?"
  },
  {
    "id": 168,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Digital Footprint",
    "options": [
      "Digital Footprint",
      "Cybersecurity",
      "Data Breach",
      "Phishing"
    ],
    "question": "What term refers to the trail of data and online activity that individuals leave behind on the internet?"
  },
  {
    "id": 169,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Algorithm",
    "options": [
      "Algorithm",
      "Code",
      "Programming Language",
      "Operating System (OS)"
    ],
    "question": "What is a step-by-step procedure or set of rules for solving a specific problem or accomplishing a specific task?"
  },
  {
    "id": 170,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Biometrics",
    "options": ["Biometrics", "Cryptography", "Firewall", "Encryption"],
    "question": "What technology involves the measurement and statistical analysis of people's unique physical and behavioral characteristics for authentication?"
  },
  {
    "id": 171,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Augmented Reality (AR)",
    "options": [
      "Augmented Reality (AR)",
      "Virtual Reality (VR)",
      "Mixed Reality (MR)",
      "Simulated Reality (SR)"
    ],
    "question": "What technology overlays digital information or virtual objects on the real world, typically viewed through a device like a smartphone?"
  },
  {
    "id": 172,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "JavaScript",
    "options": ["JavaScript", "Python", "Java", "C++"],
    "question": "What programming language is commonly used for web development to add interactivity and dynamic behavior to websites?"
  },
  {
    "id": 173,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "Hacker",
    "options": ["Hacker", "Cracker", "Phreaker", "Script Kiddie"],
    "question": "What term refers to a person who seeks to exploit weaknesses in computer systems or networks for malicious purposes?"
  },
  {
    "id": 174,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "3D Printing",
    "options": [
      "3D Printing",
      "Laser Printing",
      "Inkjet Printing",
      "Offset Printing"
    ],
    "question": "What technology creates physical objects layer by layer based on a digital model?"
  },
  {
    "id": 175,
    "subject": "ICT",
    "correctAnswer": "API (Application Programming Interface)",
    "options": [
      "API (Application Programming Interface)",
      "GUI (Graphical User Interface)",
      "CPU (Central Processing Unit)",
      "RAM (Random Access Memory)"
    ],
    "question": "What term refers to a set of rules and protocols that allows different software applications to communicate with each other?"
  },

  {
    "id": 176,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "Mount Everest",
    "options": ["Mount Everest", "K2", "Makalu", "Lhotse"],
    "question": "Which is the highest mountain in the world?"
  },
  {
    "id": 177,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "Paris",
    "options": ["Paris", "Rome", "London", "Berlin"],
    "question": "What is the capital city of France?"
  },
  {
    "id": 178,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "Mona Lisa",
    "options": [
      "Mona Lisa",
      "The Starry Night",
      "Guernica",
      "The Persistence of Memory"
    ],
    "question": "Which famous painting was created by Leonardo da Vinci?"
  },
  {
    "id": 179,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "William Shakespeare",
    "options": [
      "William Shakespeare",
      "Charles Dickens",
      "Jane Austen",
      "Mark Twain"
    ],
    "question": "Who is often regarded as the greatest playwright in the English language?"
  },
  {
    "id": 180,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "Amazon River",
    "options": [
      "Amazon River",
      "Nile River",
      "Mississippi River",
      "Yangtze River"
    ],
    "question": "Which river is the longest in the world?"
  },
  {
    "id": 181,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Great Wall of China",
    "options": [
      "The Great Wall of China",
      "The Colosseum",
      "Machu Picchu",
      "Taj Mahal"
    ],
    "question": "Which is the longest wall in the world?"
  },
  {
    "id": 182,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "Albert Einstein",
    "options": [
      "Albert Einstein",
      "Isaac Newton",
      "Galileo Galilei",
      "Stephen Hawking"
    ],
    "question": "Who is known for the theory of relativity and the equation E=mc^2?"
  },
  {
    "id": 183,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Vatican City",
    "options": ["The Vatican City", "Monaco", "San Marino", "Liechtenstein"],
    "question": "What is the smallest independent state in the world by land area?"
  },
  {
    "id": 184,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Statue of Liberty",
    "options": [
      "The Statue of Liberty",
      "The Eiffel Tower",
      "The Colosseum",
      "The Great Pyramid of Giza"
    ],
    "question": "Which iconic landmark was a gift from France to the United States?"
  },
  {
    "id": 185,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "Australia",
    "options": ["Australia", "Canada", "Russia", "China"],
    "question": "Which country is known as the 'Land Down Under'?"
  },
  {
    "id": 186,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "Leonardo da Vinci",
    "options": ["Leonardo da Vinci", "Michelangelo", "Raphael", "Donatello"],
    "question": "Who painted the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?"
  },
  {
    "id": 187,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Great Barrier Reef",
    "options": [
      "The Great Barrier Reef",
      "The Grand Canyon",
      "The Serengeti",
      "The Amazon Rainforest"
    ],
    "question": "Which is the world's largest coral reef system?"
  },
  {
    "id": 188,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The United Nations (UN)",
    "options": [
      "The United Nations (UN)",
      "NATO",
      "European Union (EU)",
      "African Union (AU)"
    ],
    "question": "What international organization was established after World War II to promote peace and cooperation?"
  },
  {
    "id": 189,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Pyramids of Giza",
    "options": [
      "The Pyramids of Giza",
      "The Sphinx",
      "The Valley of the Kings",
      "Karnak Temple"
    ],
    "question": "Which ancient Egyptian monuments are among the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World?"
  },
  {
    "id": 190,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Great Depression",
    "options": [
      "The Great Depression",
      "The Roaring Twenties",
      "The Prohibition Era",
      "The Jazz Age"
    ],
    "question": "What was the severe worldwide economic depression that took place in the 1930s?"
  },
  {
    "id": 191,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "Nelson Mandela",
    "options": [
      "Nelson Mandela",
      "Desmond Tutu",
      "F.W. de Klerk",
      "Steve Biko"
    ],
    "question": "Who was South Africa's first black president and anti-apartheid revolutionary?"
  },
  {
    "id": 192,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "Vincent van Gogh",
    "options": [
      "Vincent van Gogh",
      "Pablo Picasso",
      "Salvador Dalí",
      "Claude Monet"
    ],
    "question": "Which artist is known for his painting 'Starry Night'?"
  },
  {
    "id": 193,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Moon",
    "options": ["The Moon", "Mars", "Venus", "Jupiter"],
    "question": "Which celestial body is Earth's natural satellite?"
  },
  {
    "id": 194,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Great Sphinx of Giza",
    "options": [
      "The Great Sphinx of Giza",
      "The Statue of Liberty",
      "The Colosseum",
      "The Parthenon"
    ],
    "question": "What is a mythical creature with the body of a lion and the head of a human?"
  },
  {
    "id": 195,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Cold War",
    "options": [
      "The Cold War",
      "World War I",
      "World War II",
      "The Korean War"
    ],
    "question": "What period of political tension and military rivalry existed between the United States and the Soviet Union after World War II?"
  },
  {
    "id": 196,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Declaration of Independence",
    "options": [
      "The Declaration of Independence",
      "The Bill of Rights",
      "The Constitution",
      "The Emancipation Proclamation"
    ],
    "question": "What document was adopted by the Continental Congress on July 4, 1776, declaring the Thirteen Colonies independent from British rule?"
  },
  {
    "id": 197,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Sahara Desert",
    "options": [
      "The Sahara Desert",
      "The Gobi Desert",
      "The Atacama Desert",
      "The Arabian Desert"
    ],
    "question": "Which desert is the largest hot desert in the world?"
  },
  {
    "id": 198,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The United Kingdom (UK)",
    "options": ["The United Kingdom (UK)", "France", "Germany", "Italy"],
    "question": "Which country is composed of England, Scotland, Wales, and Northern Ireland?"
  },
  {
    "id": 199,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Louvre",
    "options": [
      "The Louvre",
      "The British Museum",
      "The Metropolitan Museum of Art",
      "The Vatican Museums"
    ],
    "question": "Which museum in Paris is home to Leonardo da Vinci's 'Mona Lisa'?"
  },
  {
    "id": 200,
    "subject": "General Knowledge",
    "correctAnswer": "The Nobel Peace Prize",
    "options": [
      "The Nobel Peace Prize",
      "The Pulitzer Prize",
      "The Booker Prize",
      "The Grammy Award"
    ],
    "question": "What prestigious international award is given annually to individuals and organizations that have made significant contributions to peace?"
  }
]
